JOSHUA LITCHFIELD (508) 572-6242

☑ joshualitchfield@me.com **⑤** joshualitchfield.com **⑥** joshualitchfield **⑤** josh_litchfield

PROFILE

I am always striving for continual improvement. I joined Startup Institute to jump start my career. In the future, I would like to work at a small to medium sized design-centric firm that focuses on team, process, and learning. I want to build really great products and experiences.

EXPERIENCE

Web Design Student at Startup Institute // OCT 2015 - PRES. Selected from a competitive applicant pool for this eight week immersive program. Startup Institute helps individuals to develop the skills, mindset, and network to be high-impact at a high-growth company.

Coursework: HTML + CSS, jQuery, Javascript, user-centered design, rapid prototyping, navigation and flow, and Typography.

Co-founder & Creative Director, Mike McNeil Org. // MAR 2009 - PRES. MMO raises tens of thousands of dollars each year and donates it to MGH benefitting cancer research as well as other non-profit causes Mikey believed in. Our largest event is an annual 450+ person pub crawl.

Designer for all merchandise, print, and web design. Formed partnership with Harpoon Brewery and Somerville Brewing Co. Team role planning and execution of all events.

Honoree, The One Hundred, Massachusetts General Hospital

UX/UI Designer at Sermo // JUN 2014-OCT 2015

Worked with PM to define MVP for market research tool. Finished wireframes and prototypes for the same tool. Designed and coded responsive emails for several products. Assisted in reviews and design of iOS app.

Web Designer at Sermo // MAR 2011 - JUN 2014

Design and code landing pages and banner ads. Upon completion of campaign, I pulled and analyzed raw data then created metrics reports.

Clients included Microsoft, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Genentech, Janssen Pharmaceuticals, and Shire, US

Graphic Design Intern at Harpoon Brewery // JAN 2009 - DEC 2009 Designed custom signage, communication material, t-shirts, magazine advertisements, and packaging.

EDUCATION

University of Massachusetts, Lowell // CLASS OF 2008 Bachelor of Fine Arts, Graphic Design

SKILLS & TOOLS

Expert Knowledge

Sketch 3 Photoshop CC Illustrator CC Semantic HTML5 / CSS3 Rapid Prototyping UX/UI Design

Advanced Knowledge

Sublime Text 3 **Email on Acid** Content Strategy

Working Knowledge

Responsive Design Git & Github Google Analytics **Client Relations**

ASSOCIATIONS

AIGA, Boston

INTERESTS

Cooking & Food Mixology Technology Travel **TED Talks**